<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Daniel Ops</title><link>https://danielchg.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Daniel Ops</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 15:59:54 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://danielchg.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SR-IOV on OpenShift</title><link>https://danielchg.github.io/posts/sriov-on-openshift/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 15:59:54 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://danielchg.github.io/posts/sriov-on-openshift/</guid><description>Table of Contents Table of Contents Introduction What is SR-IOV Describe environment used for this article How to use it on OpenShift Install SR-IOV operator Validate SR-IOV support on the NIC Concepts and configurations Configure VFs Deploy workloads that use VFs as second interface Troubleshooting Conclusions Resources Introduction At the moment of this writing, the big actors on 5G, are making a huge effort to transform their workloads to be deployed as cloud native apps.</description></item><item><title>How to configure dnsmasq for dual stack ipv4/ipv6</title><link>https://danielchg.github.io/posts/dnsmasq-for-dualstack/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 13:19:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://danielchg.github.io/posts/dnsmasq-for-dualstack/</guid><description>Table of Contents Table of Contents Scenario Dnsmasq Installation Configuration Common config per interface DHCP options for ipv4 DHCP options for ipv6 IP reservation DNS resolution for dual stack DNS resolution for wildcard subdomains Troubleshooting Summary Scenario Nowadays it is more and more common to start working with networks that support ipv6, in order to adapt our environment to the new version of the ip stack. Also we want to keep our ipv4 configuration for legacy applications.</description></item><item><title>OpenShift hardening using the Compliance Operator</title><link>https://danielchg.github.io/posts/compliance-operator/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 17:45:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://danielchg.github.io/posts/compliance-operator/</guid><description>Table of Contents Table of Contents Introduction Compliance Operator Requirements Installation Configure and run scans Create ScanSettings Create ScanSettingBinding Get results Remediations Conclusions Links Introduction When we talk about Cyber Security, there are a lot of aspects to be focused on to keep our services secure, and from the point of view of the platform, during all Internet years, the industry has created some standards in order to keep minimum requirements so that our infrastructure is secure enough to prevent unauthorized access or DoS.</description></item><item><title>Create an OCP and OLM mirror with oc-mirror plugin</title><link>https://danielchg.github.io/posts/oc-mirror/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 17:44:18 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://danielchg.github.io/posts/oc-mirror/</guid><description>Table of Content Table of Content Context oc-mirror plugin Install Configure Create a mirror Configure credentials to pull OCP images Deploy disconnected registry Create mirror to file Create mirror from file to registry ImageContentSourcePolicies objects Conclusions Links Context At the moment of this writing, I&amp;rsquo;m working in the Telco 5G area at Red Hat, where we work mostly deploying OCP (OpenShift Container Platform) on bare metal. These deployments are focused on clusters that will be placed in remote locations with no Internet access due to security constraints and/or network designs.</description></item></channel></rss>